<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>what I do on Mathematical Michael</title>
    <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in what I do on Mathematical Michael</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpilosov.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>architect &amp; engineer</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/engineer/</guid>
      <description>Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve Built (&amp;amp; Why) I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much from free software, and want to give back by making the things I build available to others. I would characterize my work as falling into one of three categories:
improving the research &amp;amp; development experience educational resources software to support computational science I believe in making complicated things easier for people to digest, and I often feel that software helps achieve that goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>estimation</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/research/</guid>
      <description>Research If there&amp;rsquo;s one theme that unifies my research experience, it&amp;rsquo;s estimation.
Most of my time was spent creating new methods to estimate truth from data, which is polluted by observational noise in the measurement process.
I developed a new statistical method to estimate model parameters from noisy data (i.e., &amp;ldquo;fitting a model&amp;rdquo;). I used a measure-theoretic framework (developed by my advisor Dr. Troy Butler) to solve a stochastic inverse problem, one involving estimation of a true parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>art</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/art/</guid>
      <description>Probably Art I combine art, math, and machines to build wonderful things.
Unfortunately, I have done a bad job of documenting these projects.
Please pardon this Work-In-Progress. I promise to fill this page with content shortly. My priority was first to document all of the other projects I&amp;rsquo;ve done.
In short, I have been making digital art (which occasionally becomes physical) with the use of randomness since 2013. I suppose it was a bit of a harbinger for my academic career: I wanted to explore the impact of probability distributions on some (here, visual) outcome through the use of software built and run on computers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
