<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematical Michael</title>
    <link>https://mpilosov.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mathematical Michael</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpilosov.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>art</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/art/</guid>
      <description>Probably Art I combine art, math, and machines to build wonderful things.
Start with today. Show biggest achievement.
How did we get here? Probability-Dependent Generative Artwork. It was the first experience I had with GUIs, and then the same theme tied together this project. Real-time visualization of randomness, now used to aid in design.
I want to find more projects like this.
Description Describe your relationship to art.
History Moving Pictures summer 2013 History&amp;hellip; early Gallery Project Probably Art context Project Present code exists here and needs major reorganization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>estimation</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/research/</guid>
      <description>Research MUD The Oracle (AKA the Monte-Carlo Calculator)
talk about research, wanting to make something useful, something to share. The Oracle is a web app I built to help me make quick estimates without keeping them in my head (and then share them!).
Often we find &amp;ldquo;back-of-the-napkin&amp;rdquo; calculations to be useful&amp;hellip; randall munroe what if &amp;hellip; fermi problems wiki &amp;hellip; TK TK TK
It is deployed with #kubernetes on #google-cloud-platform and is built with #python using #flask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>who I am</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Third Generation Artist, Machine Learning Architect, and Scientific Software Engineer.
I am Michael Pilosov, PhD I enable people to answer their toughest questions by using mathematics to quanitfy and reduce uncertainty.
write code for people, not machines Developing new software tools or dealing with challenging data can be major barriers to experts in any field; making something that enables reproduciblity, efficiency, and innovation requires different skillsets. Using my technical expertise, I build bridges over those barriers, enabling others to do their very best work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>architect &amp; engineer</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/software/</guid>
      <description>Software Contributions I learned so much from free software and feel the need to contribute back. When I do things now, I make them available so that people can learn from my trials and tribulations.
I believe in making complicated things easier for people to digest, and software contributions is one way I do it.
ML Starter-Packs ml-starter-packs is a Github organization I created to house relatively polished projects for public consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>connect</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>get in touch Let’s work together!
Need me to teach a workshop?
Help improve your developer experience (both cloud and workstation)?
Modernize your Python packaging process?
Build a software products?
Something else?
Your email: Your message: Send </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>run events</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/outreach/</guid>
      <description>Stochastic Poker current min max action Start New Game What&#39;s Going on? A coin is being flipped automatically.
Heads +1, Tails -1. Keep a running sum.
This webpage is your &#34;hand&#34;. Find some friends and show them how to get a hand of their own. Choose a unit of value with which to gamble (candy, dimes, chips, etc.). There are six rounds of betting, corresponding to each tick mark in the chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>etc</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/other/</guid>
      <description>More Projects Consider this a dumping ground for links to things I want to show people I&amp;rsquo;ve done.
Academic Research I worked to develop new ways of quantifying and reducing uncertainty.
Academic Research Academic Research Mind the Grow here I embed a link in a sentence to give context
Code Math Club Repository Archive Twitterbots Prior Oracle Twitter Account Consulting Visit Website </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
