<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematical Michael</title>
    <link>https://mpilosov.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mathematical Michael</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpilosov.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Oracle</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/oracle/</guid>
      <description>The Oracle This project is the culmination of many repeated efforts to estimate some quantity that can be expressed through a basic math equation.
I frequently use it in place of &amp;ldquo;back-of-the-napkin&amp;rdquo; math, especially when it involves a lot of uncertainty such as when estimating the cost of a cloud compute job for clients. It can be used in many ways, the imagination of the user is the practical limit (other than the number of variables involved&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>art</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/art/</guid>
      <description>Probably Art I combine art, math, and machines to build wonderful things.
I have been making digital art (which occasionally becomes physical) with the use of randomness since 2013. I suppose it was a bit of a harbinger for my academic career: I wanted to explore the impact of probability distributions on some (here, visual) outcome through the use of software built and run on computers.
My art projects were actually how I learned to program, they were how I pushed the boundaries of my knowledge in both hardware and software development (it started with scripting in Matlab&amp;hellip;), and how I found a creative outlet for expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>architect &amp; engineer</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/engineer/</guid>
      <description>Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve Built (&amp;amp; Why) I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much from free software, and want to give back by making the things I build available to others. I would characterize my work as falling into one of three categories:
improving the research &amp;amp; development experience educational resources software to support computational science I believe in making complicated things easier for people to digest, and I often feel that software helps achieve that goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>who I am</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Third Generation Artist, Machine Learning Architect, and Scientific Software Engineer.
I am Michael Pilosov I enable people to answer their toughest questions by using mathematics to quantify and reduce uncertainty.
write code for people, not machines Developing new software tools or dealing with challenging data can be major barriers to experts in any field; making something that enables reproduciblity, efficiency, and innovation requires different skillsets. Using my technical expertise, I build bridges over those barriers, enabling others to do their very best work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>estimation</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/research/</guid>
      <description>Research If there&amp;rsquo;s one theme that unifies my research experience, it&amp;rsquo;s estimation.
Most of my time was spent creating new methods to estimate truth from data, which is polluted by observational noise in the measurement process.
I developed a new statistical method to estimate model parameters from noisy data (i.e., &amp;ldquo;fitting a model&amp;rdquo;). I used a measure-theoretic framework (developed by my advisor Dr. Troy Butler) to solve a stochastic inverse problem, one involving estimation of a true parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stochastic poker</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/poker/</guid>
      <description>Stochastic Poker Context: I ran an event during my tenure on the executive board of the CU Denver Math Club which presented several &amp;ldquo;mathematical games,&amp;rdquo; which included one novel invention which required a bit of software engineering in Javascript to accomplish. You are seeing a refactored version below.
current min max action Start New Game What&#39;s Going on? A coin is being flipped automatically.
Heads +1, Tails -1. Keep a running sum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cafelytics</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/mtg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/mtg/</guid>
      <description>Mind the Grow Mind the Grow was a company I started with the hopes of writing and supporting software to help with agricultural planning.
The scope is not some complicated forecasting model based on historical data, but rather a decision-making toolbox (&amp;ldquo;should I buy more land?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;what mix of crops should I plant?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;how should I plan crop rotations?&amp;rdquo;, etc), focused on solving a set of problems I encountered when volunteering with a coffee cooperative in 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>connect</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>get in touch Let’s work together! Do you need me to:
Teach a workshop? Help improve your developer experience? Modernize your Python packaging process? Build a software product? Something else?
Schedule a Call </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containerized JupyterHub</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/jhub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/jhub/</guid>
      <description>Containerized JupyterHub In early 2017, I set up a docker-based deployment of JupyterHub on a server in my academic department and onboarded almost every professor using Python to use it. I created development environments suited to each course and enabled professors to give their students a browser-based development environment which allowed them to be productive from day one, no setup required.
jupyterhub-deploy-docker To support the statisticians in my department who were using R instead of Python, I built a containerized RStudio + RShiny server that would launch through JupyterHub via an nginx-proxy server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Dev Env</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/stats/</guid>
      <description>RStudio + RShiny Every time I had to reproduce results that were produced in R I had a hard time, so I containerized RStudio and RShiny in order to have a development environment that would work across operating systems and cloud deployments.
stats-server I was able to also proxy these services through JupyterHub so these environments can be available as options in my deployment template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mlflow example</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/mlflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/mlflow/</guid>
      <description>mlflow reference deployment I discovered mlflow while researching experiment management solutions on a client engagement. I find it strikes a perfect balance of being flexible enough to be useful in many contexts and deployment configurations, while not doing &amp;ldquo;too much.&amp;rdquo;
To help myself spin up a containerized mlflow deployment with PostGreSQL and S3 backends, I crafted a template project that demonstrated assessments of several natural language processing models. In order to answer &amp;ldquo;How does this machine-learning model work for our specific use-case?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microservices for ml</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/micro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/micro/</guid>
      <description>Microservices Workshop I volunteered to teach junior engineers and architects from other capabilities at my company about issues related to &amp;ldquo;ML Ops,&amp;rdquo; or the operationalization of machine-learning models. What this means in practice is applying the last decade of developments from the web-world to machine-learning use-cases (e.g. exposing functionality via API calls). This was part of a larger &amp;ldquo;ML Academy&amp;rdquo; the students were part of, and my lesson came towards the end of the curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>actual architecture</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/njh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/njh/</guid>
      <description>Actual Architecture A Graphical User Interface was built to assist in the parametric design of the exterior of a new hospital wing in Denver, CO.
Six colors in varying proportions (three primary colors each with an accent) were sampled at random (with replacement) to define the visual aesthetic of the building.
It is located at the intersection of Colfax Street &amp;amp; Colorado Boulevard and was open to the public in Spring 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ml monorepo</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/mono/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/mono/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Mono Repo During one of my consulting engagements, I encountered a client with a situation that I feel plagues many organizations who have embraced micro-service architecture patterns. I am an advocate of the principle of separation that this design decision reflects, but I discovered that one of the implications (splitting services out into their own repositories) led to a lot of technical debt.
Since we were working on a large legacy codebase that was being converted slowly to Python packages, it often occurred that changes would need to propagate to dozens of individual repos, each of which would need to ship a new release for use in the production system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>legislation scraping</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/legiscrapor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/legiscrapor/</guid>
      <description>Scraping Legislation with NLP Andreana Rosnik published her work for scraping legislation PDFs from government websites using natural language processing. I really loved the work and use-case:
legiscrapor is a project to web scrape and crawl through parliamentary websites of various countries around the world for legislation related to human rights issues.
My contribution was straightforward. I wanted stuff like this to be more easily usable by others, so I helped turn Andrea&amp;rsquo;s scripts into a Python package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dissertation template</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/diss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/diss/</guid>
      <description>Dissertation Template When writing my doctoral dissertation, I adopted git-flow practices and wanted to treat my PDF as a software product (I was already working at the time). I used an existing dissertation template from a student in the biology program from several years prior to my own writing, and modified it heavily to meet the new publication standards published by the university. However, my contributions also included the creation of a development environment that could be used to compile the document, since setting up LaTeX with the right set of extensions can be quite challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU-Jupyter</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/gpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/gpu/</guid>
      <description>GPU-Enabled Jupyter Images After many years of running CPU-only JupyterHub on cloud servers, I eventually built my own workstation equipped with an Nvidia GPU. This presented me with a new problem: none of my existing containerized development environments had the required hardware support to enable the acceleration the GPU promised.
In comes gpu-jupyter, a project which provided Dockerfiles that mirrored the jupyter-docker-stacks but built on Nvidia-published base-images. I found this repository almost worked for me, so I began contributing fixes and improvements to it regularly, including the automation of building and publishing images with Github Actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tex for teachers</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/tex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/tex/</guid>
      <description>LaTeX Lesson Plans As part of my PhD program I taught several undergraduate courses. Many of these involve teaching problem-solving from word statements involving numbers.
I wanted a software-like experience to design all the lesson plans, quizzes, and exams. If I discovered a typo during teaching, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to edit multiple versions of the same document (the original and answer key), to prepare for the next semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>free web apps</title>
      <link>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/binder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpilosov.com/projects/etc/binder/</guid>
      <description>Sharing Apps (for free) One of the challenges I repeatedly encountered was that I would build some sort of web-based application for a friend or client demo, and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be bogged down with deployment concerns. I wanted to be able to share my work simply by providing a URL but (at that time) was uncomfortable with exposing services on my home network, and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to overload my minimal cloud servers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
